# PETER OKUMBE

BScHons Computer Science Graduate | Low-code Software Developer

#### CAREER OBJECTIVE

Honours Computer Science Graduate and current Mendix Trainee at LINKITSYSTEMS South Africa with 4+ years of experience in programming in various programming languages (listed under relevant skills) at an educational level. 2 years' experience of working as a Computer Science Tutor in providing consultations, assistance, and mentorship to students with regards to course work, practical assignments, and projects. Skilled in practical problem-solving tasks, articulate in communication and well versed in time management and organization. Driven by a focused desire and need for structure, faith, and positivity in life with an interest and eagerness to learn and discover more both as an individual, as well as from others. Currently interested in pursuing a career in data science (involving data analysis and/or mining), business intelligence or software (low-code) development.

# **EDUCATION**

February 2022 – June 2023 | University of Pretoria BScHons Computer Science

February 2018 - December 2021 | University of Pretoria BSc IT (Major in Computer Science & Data Science)

**January 2013 - December 2017** | Willowridge High School, Pretoria

National Senior Certificate (NSC)

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

July 2019 | Lory Park Zoo, Midrand

**Community Based Project Volunteer Work** 

- Module: JCP202 (Community-Based Project) Completed 40 hours of volunteer work at the Lory Park Zoo, situated in Midrand, Johannesburg.
- **Description:** As a team, we designed and developed an innovative feeder pulley system for the Lemur animal cages in the zoo.

- **6** 061 386 5697
- retepoku@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/ peterokumbe-65a887203/
- https://github.com/peterokumbe17
- https://peterokumbe17.github.io/

# **AWARDS**

Golden Key International Society (2019) - Top 15% Achiever's Award in field of study. https://www.goldenkey.org/

#### RELEVANT SKILLS

Programming Languages: Delphi,

SQL, C++, Python, Java.

Markup and Scripting: HTML,

CSS, PHP, JS, Nodejs.

**Operating Systems:** Windows,

Linux.

Database Systems: MySQL,

PostgreSQL, MongoDB, db4o,

BaseX, Neo4j.

Software: Microsoft Office, Adobe

XD, SAS, WEKA, IBM SPSS,

Jupyter Notebook, Mendix.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# April 2023 - Present | LINKITSYSTEMS South Africa

#### **Mendix Trainee**

 Description: Joined a bootcamp traineeship to learn about the low-code development of software applications and solutions using the <u>Mendix</u> low-code development platform in growing to become a certified Mendix developer.

# February 2023 - April 2023 | University of Pretoria

# **Computer Science Tutor**

- Module: COS221 (Introduction to Database Systems).
- Description: Consultation sessions; Group project mentorship; Marking and grading of practical assignments and project demos.

# July 2022 – November 2022 | University of Pretoria

# **Computer Science Tutor**

- Module: COS333 (Programming Languages).
- Description: Marking and grading of practical assignments.

#### July 2022 – November 2022 | University of Pretoria

## **Computer Science Tutor**

- Module: COS214 (Software Modelling).
- **Description:** Consultation sessions; Group project mentorship; Marking and grading of practical assignments and project demos.

#### March 2022 - July 2022 | University of Pretoria

#### **Computer Science Tutor**

- Module: COS332 (Computer Networks).
- Description: Marking and grading of practical assignments.

#### March 2022 - July 2022 | University of Pretoria

#### **Computer Science Tutor**

- Module: COS212 (Data Structures and Algorithms).
- **Description:** Consultation sessions; Assisting with conduction of practical assignments.

#### March 2021 – July 2021 | University of Pretoria

#### **Computer Science Tutor**

• Module: COS212 (Data Structures and Algorithms).

Frameworks: Flutter, Google

Firebase.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (fluent), Swahili

• **Description:** Consultation sessions; Assisting with conduction of practical assignments.

## July 2020 – December 2020 | University of Pretoria

#### **Computer Science Tutor**

Module: COS122 (Operating Systems).

Description: Marking and grading of practical assignments.

# **PROJECTS**

## June 2023 - Present | LINKITSYSTEMS South Africa

## **LINKIT Customer Survey Tool**

• Platform: Mendix.

 Description: An internal project proposed by LINKIT to develop a Customer Survey Tool application that allows the clients of LINKIT to answer questionnaires and provide feedback about their experiences with working alongside the LINKIT employees that partook in the development of their individual / group project/s.

#### September 2022 – October 2022 | University of Pretoria

# **COS781 Data Mining Group Project**

Module: COS781 (Data Mining).

• Description: A group project proposed by the course coordinators of the BScHons Computer Science Data Mining module (COS781) at the University of Pretoria to engage in a collaborative team project for the conduction of the mining and analyzation of data through various phases of the CRISP-DM (CRoss Industry Standard Process for Data Mining) process that involved the understanding, preparation, modelling, and evaluation of the data used. Software and programming languages used throughout the conduction of the entire project included python, as well as the WEKA and IBM SPSS software tools. Analyzation of the data involved cluster analysis and predictive classification modelling.

#### February 2022 – October 2022 | University of Pretoria

# **COS700** Research Report

Module: COS700 (Research Methods).

• Description: A research report proposed by the course coordinators of the BScHons Computer Science Research Methods and Project module (COS700) at the University of Pretoria to conduct a research report on a given topic that is derived from one of the chosen and existing research groups in the department of Computer Science under the guidance of a research supervisor in the related field of research.

## June 2021 - October 2021 | University of Pretoria

#### **COS301 Capstone Project — Coviduous**

- Module: COS301 (Software Engineering).
- Description: A group project proposed by AWS and coordinated by the course coordinators of the Final Year BSc Computer Science COS301 Software Engineering module (COS301) at the University of Pretoria. 'Coviduous' is an application that will be used to arrange and optimize office floor plans according to COVID-19 regulations in South Africa. This project aims to solve the issue of hand managing office capacity based on the country's alert level by making use of floor diagrams, desks and office space, ensuring the appropriate distance is maintained between workers who wish to return to the office. The application will allow booking and assignment of desks and office spaces for capacity management.

# March 2021 - May 2021 | University of Pretoria

# COS301 Mini Project — CrowdBook

- Module: COS301 (Software Engineering).
- Description: A group project proposed by the course coordinators of the Final Year BSc Computer Science Software Engineering module (COS301) at the University of Pretoria to create a 'CrowdBook' website and mobile application that allows users to buy, sell and rent books. Specifically targeted at students (however, should extend to the general public) to increase ease of purchasing or selling textbooks, conforming to the COVID-19 social distancing regulations allowing purchased books online to be shipped to the respective buyers.